raahi.com 2019-05-28

# Privacy Policy - Yatra : Online Travel Services Company in India

Yatra respects your privacy and recognizes the need to protect the personally identifiable information (any information by which you can be identified, such as name, gender,email address, postal address, frequent fly number, age, telephone number, etc) you share with us. We would like to assure you that we follow appropriate standards when it comes to protecting your privacy on our Sales Channel.

This Privacy Policy is applicable to persons who purchase / intend to purchase / inquire about any product(s) and / or service(s) made available by Yatra ('User') through any of Yatra's 's customer interface channels including website, mobile site, mobile app & offline channels including call centers and offices (collectively referred herein as "Sales Channels").

By using or accessing the Website or other Sales Channels, the User hereby agrees with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the contents herein. If you disagree with this Privacy Policy please do not use or access our Website or other Sales Channels.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any website(s), mobile sites and mobile apps of third parties, even if their websites/products are linked to our Website. User should take note that information and privacy practices of YATRA's business partners, advertisers, sponsors or other sites to which YATRA provides hyperlink(s), may be materially different from this Privacy Policy. Accordingly, it is recommended that you review the privacy statements and policies of any such third parties.

**Information We Collect**

With specific reference to booking/e-commerce transactions, Yatra collects the following personal sensitive information from you while transacting through Yatra:

  * Name and Gender
  * Phone Number
  * Address
  * Credit Card details
  * Date of birth in case of a child
  * Passport Number & frequent flyer number (whereever needed) 

**How the Information is used**

Yatra does not sell or trade upon any of the above foregoing information without the consent of the user or customer. The foregoing information collected from the users/customers/travellers is put to the following use:

  * Customer name, address, phone number, traveller's name and age are shared with applicable service providers like the airlines, hotels, etc., for the purpose of reservation and booking the services for the customer/traveller.
  * Information like Credit Card Details and Net Banking Details are usually collected directly by the payment gateways and banks and not by Yatra, but if ever stored or retained by us, remain internal and is never shared. 
  * These details are also shared with certain third parties only for the purpose of processing 'Cash Back & Discounts' and Charge Backs, if applicable. Information like Mobile no, e-mail address and postal address may be used for promotional purposes, unless the customer/user "opts-out" of such use.   
If you choose not - to share this information, you can still visit the Yatra website, but you may be unable to avail certain options, ours and services. 

**Cookies and Session Data**

In general, you can visit Yatra website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. We track the Internet address of the domains from which people visit us and analyze this data for trends and statistics, but the individual user remains anonymous.

Some of our web pages use "cookies" so that we can better serve you with customized information when you return to our site. Cookies are identifiers which web sites send to the browser on your computer to facilitate your next visit to our site. You can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the option to decide whether or not to accept it. The information we collect and analyze is used to improve our service to you.

**Automatic Logging of Session Data:**

Each time you access the Website your session data gets logged. Session data consists of the User's IP address, operating system and type of browser software being used and the activities conducted by the User while on the Website. We collect session data because it helps us analyze User's choices, browsing pattern including the frequency of visits and duration for which a User is logged on. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems. The aforesaid information cannot identify any User personally. However, it is possible to determine a User's Internet Service Provider (ISP), and the approximate geographic location of User's point of connectivity from the IP address.

**With whom your Personal Information is Shared**

With specific reference to third party Non Personally identifiable information advertising, we use third-party service providers to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and sometimes on this site. They may collect anonymous information about your visits to our website, and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use information about your visits to this and other websites to target advertisements for goods and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a 'pixel tag', which is industry standard technology used by most major websites. No personally identifiable information is collected or used in this process. Such third parties do not know your name, phone number, address, email address, or any personally identifying information. 

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this anonymous information used by our third party service provider, please email at [support@yatra.com](mailto:support@yatra.com)

Please note: Even after your account is terminated, we retain your data for as long as we have a legitimate purpose to do so (and in accordance with applicable law), including to assist with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may retain and disclose such data pursuant to this Privacy Policy after your account has been terminated

**Disclosure of information**

We may, in good faith, in our sole discretion and without any notice to you , disclose your personal sensitive information to protect ourselves from any liability or fraud or similar situation, to respond to judicial processes, legitimate requests from any third parties, warrants or equivalent by law enforcement trials or authorities, to investigate fraud or other wrongdoing or as otherwise required or necessary in order to comply with applicable law or to protect our legitimate interests or those of users. We may also, disclose personal sensitive information if it is reasonably necessary in our opinion to protect the rights or property of Yatra or any of its affiliates or any third party or to avoid injury to any person.

The user's personal information may be disclosed for regulatory/ internal compliance and audit(s).

Yatra takes appropriate steps to protect the information you share with us. We have implemented technology and security features and strict policy guidelines to safeguard the privacy of your personally identifiable information from unauthorized access and improper use or disclosure. Please contact us on legal@yatra.com to obtain names and addresses of the specific entities that shall have access to your personal information in a given transaction.

Yatra will continue to enhance its security procedures as new technology becomes available, and ensures that its security procedures are compliant with current applicable regulations.

If our privacy policy changes in the future, it will be posted here and a new effective date will be shown. You should access our privacy policy regularly to ensure you understand our current policies.

**How You Can Opt-Out of receiving Promotional Emails.**

Check your User Profile Information available and stored with Yatra under the section ["My Profile"](https://secure.yatra.com/manage-bookings/allbookings#/profile)

To get user profile deleted please send an email to – [support@yatra.com](mailto:support@yatra.com) Check your booking history under the section ["My Bookings"](https://secure.yatra.com/myaccount/user/index.html).

In order to download your booking invoices and vouchers, please visit the section ["Tickets/ Vouchers"](https://secure.yatra.com/manage-bookings/allbookings?#/list?companyId=YT&action=sms_email&page=1) under "My account"

The updated policy stand s effective as of May 25, 2018

Android App Permissions required to use various features in our app:

In order to have a better experience and to use all features in the app, we need below permissions to be used in our android app:

**-CAMERA:**  
We will not access your photos or camera without first getting your permission and we will never scan or import your photo library or camera roll. If you give us permission to access photos or your camera, we will only use images that you specifically choose to share with us. 

**-Contacts:**  
We will not scan or import your contacts stored on your phone without first getting your explicit permission. We will only use the contact information to help you find friends or contacts who use Yatra App, if you choose to do so, and we will not use contact information for any other purpose without first getting your separate explicit permission.

**-Calendar:**  
This permission enables us to put your travel plan on your calendar.

**-Location:**  
We will not gather or use the specific location of your mobile device (by using, for example, GPS or Bluetooth) without first getting your explicit permission. And if you choose to share location information but later change your mind, you will always have the ability to stop sharing. Please note that this does not include IP address. The permissions will benefit the user location specific deals and provide you a personalized experience with timezone.

**-SMS:**  
This application reads, uploads and syntactic analyses text messages from travel providers within the app for any flight and train PNR booking messages. We use this information to provides updates on PNR status, flight and train delays. This information is stored in a secured environment and always transmitted using SSL.

**-GET ACCOUNTS:**  
This permission enables us to know about details of your account(s) on your mobile device.this will help you to get register on the Platform by logging into online accounts you may have with Third Party social networking sites (e.g. Facebook, Twitter, Google Login); each such account.

**-ACCESS_WIFI_STATE:**  
By using Wi-Fi connection details, we provide you a seamless experience depending upon your network such as image loading process. We try to use this information to optimise the app's performance on slow networks.

**-Third Party:**  
The User allow the Owner to provide its services to third party services' accounts for Displaying content from external platforms, SPAM protection, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Infrastructure monitoring, Content commenting, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Location-based interactions, Social features, Contacting the User, User database management, Targeted Advertising and Remarketing and behavioral targeting.

**The other information that we collect-**

  * Analytics
Google Analytics, Appsflyer, Facebook Ads conversion tracking, Google Tag Manager

Omniture- Cookies, Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

  * Infrastructure monitoring

Crashlytics- Geographic position, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

  * Location-based interactions

Geographical locations

  * Unique device identification

This Application may track Users by storing a unique identifier of their device, for analytics purposes or for storing Users' preferences.

Thank you for using Yatra!
